(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-01T13:35:25.565818",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
のーじゃ！
Noja!
のーじゃー！
Nojaa!
めっちゃエコーがかかっちゃった
There's so much echo!
めっちゃエコーがかかっちゃったのじゃ！
There's so much echo, noja!
あれあれ？メラメラ？あちちメラメラ！
Huh? Burning? Hot burning!
遊びまーほ、ホロライブ遊びまわりたいゴリラクス担当の引き消し屋サラマンダー！あちちメラなのだじゃ！
Playing around—Hololive's play-around-wanting gorilla-relax-in-charge fire extinguisher Salamander! Hot burning, noja!
お主ら今日は、今日も元気？いい一日を過ごせたかの？
You guys, are you well today too? Did you have a good day?
お仕事とかじゃったかの？お仕事とか、学校とかじゃった？
Was it work? Or perhaps school?
もしかして、わしの歌枠を、歌配信を、すっごい楽しみにし、てたんじゃないの？
Could it be you were really looking forward to my singing stream?
わしの歌配信があるからお仕事頑張れたよとかのひともいるんじゃないの？どうじゃどうじゃ？今日休みだった？休みもいいの。
Aren't there people who could work hard because of my singing stream? How about that? Was today a day off? Days off are great too.
これからいい一日になる、一日になる。そうじゃ、わしがね、お主らの1日をもっともっといい一日にしちゃうのじゃ！
From now on it'll be a good day. That's right, I'll make your day even better, noja!
のーじゃのーじゃ！夜から仕事？じゃあ仕事の前にわしの歌を聴いて元気にするのがいいと思うのじゃ。
Noja noja! Work starting at night? Then I think it's best to listen to my songs before work to cheer up!
元気を、元気を出すのがいいと思うのじゃ！わしの為にやることを早めに終わらせた？やったのじゃ！
I think getting energized is best! You finished things early for my sake? Yay, noja!
いつもさ、わしさ、配信さ、最近ずっと19時から、19時からなんじゃけどちょっと早いよね？ちょっと早めの時間に配信いつも始めるんじゃが
Always, you know, my streams lately have been starting at 7 PM, but isn't that a bit early? I usually start streams a bit early, but...
わしの為に時間とかね合わせてくれてありがとういつも。うん、リアタイするのってやっぱスケジュールとかさ、その都合がね、あるじゃろ？
Thank you always for adjusting your time for me. Yeah, watching in real time requires scheduling and convenience, right?
だから合わせるの大変だと思うんじゃが、ありがとうなのじゃ！嬉しいのじゃ！宿題やりながら聞いてる？いいこと、勤勉なのはいいことですのじゃ。
So I think it's hard to match, but thank you, noja! I'm happy, noja! Listening while doing homework? That's good, being diligent is a good thing, noja!
作業用BGMにしてほしいのじゃ！ちょうどいい時間！やったのじゃ！
I want you to use it as work BGM! Perfect timing! Yay, noja!
この日のために生きてたかも知れない？そう思ってもらえるように、そう思ってもらえるように頑張りますのじゃ。
You might have been living for this day? I'll do my best so you can feel that way, noja.
あのね、あの、お主らが多分わしが歌うとこ聴きたいんじゃないかなって曲もね、今日ご用意してきたので一番最後に、一番最後に持ってくるとんじゃ。
You know, the songs you probably want to hear me sing, I've prepared those too, so I'll bring them at the very, very end, noja.
やっぱボカロ歌うか。ボカロも歌うのじゃ。ボカロも歌うけど、あの、なんだじゃ？ボカロ、最初から全曲ボカロなのは
Should I sing Vocaloid? I'll sing Vocaloid too. I'll sing Vocaloid, but, you know? Vocaloid, having all Vocaloid songs from the start...
ちょっと、あの、もっといっぱいの人に聴いてもらいたいと思ったから、あのボカロ以外の曲もね、用意してきたのじゃ！うん。
I thought I wanted even more people to listen, so I prepared songs other than Vocaloid too, noja! Yeah.
もしあの今日ね聴きたかった曲が聴けなかったとしてもね、あの、こん、今後？今後たくさんね、あの歌配信やっていきたいと思うからまた今後にも期待していただけると嬉しいですのじゃ！
Even if the song you wanted to hear today couldn't be played, I plan to do many singing streams in the future, so I'd be happy if you look forward to it, noja!
水こぼしちゃった。のじゃ。ちょっ、ちょっ、ティッシュ、ティッシュ。
I spilled water. Noja. Wait, tissue, tissue.
私は一週間記念が待ちきれないいきき
I can't wait for the one-week anniversary!
たのしみだのーに
Looking forward to it~
わくわくやのー
So excited~
たのしみだのー
Looking forward to it~
のちうちの記念日なのにー！
Even though it's Nochi-uchi's anniversary!
やったー！
Yay!
こんばんめらだのー！
Good evening Mela!
配信たのしみにしてたよおおおお！！
I've been looking forward to the stream!!
まいしみーに！
Looking forward to it!
ちょっと待つのじゃ
Wait a minute.
落ち着くのじゃ、落ち着くのじゃ
Calm down, calm down.
なんかあの……
Um, like...
紙コップに水を入れてるんじゃが
I put water in a paper cup,
ちょっと触るとね、ぐにゃっほれちゃうから
and if you touch it, it'll get all wobbly so,
要注意、要注意ですのじゃ。よし。
caution, extreme caution! Okay.
まあ、こんなんでいいだろう。
Well, this should be fine.
うん。落ち着くのじゃ。
Yup. Calm down.
やっぱあの……わしが歌うとこ……
I mean... where I sing...
あ！
Ah!
デビュー1周年、1周年……
Wait, debut 1st anniversary? 1st anniversary!?
1周年じゃない、もうだめだ。
Not 1st anniversary, no way.
気か早い、気か早い、もうだめじゃ。
Too soon, too soon, no good.
もう焦りまくってるのじゃ。大焦りですのじゃ。
I'm totally panicking. Super panicking.
デビュー1週間、1週間、1週間が経ちましたのじゃ！
One week since my debut has passed!
1週間、まだそんな1週間も経ってないイメージなんじゃが
One week... doesn't feel like it's been a whole week yet,
意外と時間が経つのは早いもの。
but time really flies surprisingly fast.
1周年じゃないのじゃ。
It's not the 1st anniversary.
ちょっと間違えたのじゃ。1周年はちょっとあのミスったのじゃ。
I made a mistake. I messed up on the 1st anniversary.
似てるじゃん！
They sound similar!
似てるのじゃ、1周年と1週間。
1st anniversary and 1 week sound similar.
うん、ちょっと、1周年だったら早すぎなのじゃ。
Yeah, 1st anniversary would be way too early.
これからも頑張るからいっぱい応援してほしいのですのじゃ！
I'll keep doing my best, so I hope you'll cheer me on lots!
さあ、1週間経ったわしの歌を
Now, I want you to listen to my singing
聞きたいのじゃ？聞きたいのじゃ？
after one week. You want to hear it?
お顔の下を見てお歌を聞きたい、可能お主ら！
You guys who want to look at my face and listen to me sing!
そろそろお歌聴きたくなってきたんじゃないの？
Aren't you starting to want to hear me sing soon?
聴きたくなってきたお主らは高評価ボタンを押してほしいのじゃ！
If you want to listen, please hit the like button!
グッドボタンを押してほしいのじゃ、プリーズ！
Please press the good button, please!
押してほしいのじゃ、お願いしまーすのじゃ！
I want you to press it, please!
もうした？やったのじゃ！お願いもしたところで
Already did? Yay! Now that I've asked,
そろそろお歌を歌う準備をしていくのじゃ！
it's about time I get ready to sing!
よいしょ！
Heave-ho!
のじゃー！
Nojaaa!
サラマンダーは高評価で成長するタイプ。
Salamanders are the type that grow with high ratings.
人間の仕組みは分かんないけど、サラマンダーの仕組み的には、
I don't know how humans work, but structurally for salamanders,
サラマンダーにはね、高評価を与えるといいのじゃ。
giving salamanders high ratings is good.
評価されると嬉しいですのじゃ。
I'm happy when I get rated.
やったのじゃー！
Yay!
よし。
Okay.
お歌をね、歌おうと思ってあのーセットリストみたいな歌う曲一覧を用意してきたんじゃが、最初緊張しちゃうと思うから、緊張しても歌える曲をね最初に持って来たのじゃ。
I thought I'd sing, so I prepared a setlist of songs to sing, but since I'll probably be nervous at first, I brought a song I can sing even when nervous as the first one.
あ、そう、左下をご覧なさい。
Ah, right, look at the bottom left.
えーと、このね歌配信はジョイサウンドさんのカラオケを使用させていただいているので、
Um, since this singing stream uses Joysound's karaoke,
歌唱部分の切り抜き歌ってるトコ、音楽が乗っているところの動画切り抜きは禁止ですのじゃ！
clipping the singing parts, where I'm singing or where music plays, is prohibited!
お主ら、お気をつけてくださいのじゃ。うん。よし。
You guys, please be careful. Yup. Okay.
最初の曲は、こちら。
The first song is this one.
ちょっと緊張しても歌える曲を持ってきましたのじゃ。
I brought a song I can sing even if I'm a bit nervous.
今ちょっと緊張してて、緊張してて息が上がっていて、
Right now I'm a bit nervous, my breathing is shallow,
早速、早速息が上がっていて、
and right away my breathing is already shallow,
これきゅくらりんですか？きゅくらりんじゃないのじゃ。
Is this Kyu-kurarin? It's not Kyu-kurarin.
睡眠不足はキテレツの曲なのじゃ。キテレツの曲なのじゃ。
Suimin Busoku is a song from Kiteretsu. It's a Kiteretsu song.
お主ら眠いんじゃないの？
Aren't you guys sleepy?
現代のお主ら、現代のお主らはなかなか眠たいお主らが多いんじゃないの？
You modern folks, aren't there a lot of sleepy people among you modern folks?
わしのおはよう朝活配信を見たりして、朝活配信を見たりして夜も昨日もね遊ぼうまりたらのコラボ配信をして、なかなか眠たいお主らが多いんじゃないのと思ったので、
Seeing you watch my morning streams, and having collab streams like Korabo last night, I thought there must be many sleepy people,
眠たい、そうコロスケのやつ、そうそうそう。眠たいお主ら向けにこんな曲を用意してきたのじゃ。
so for you sleepy folks, yeah, Korosuke's thing, exactly. I prepared a song like this.
よいしょ。ちょっと1曲目だから音量感とか大きいとかちっちゃいとかあったら教えてほしいのじゃ。
Heave-ho. Since it's the first song, please let me know if the volume is too loud or too soft.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
歌います！睡眠不足！
I'll sing it! Suimin Busoku!
キンコンカンコン、キンコンカン
Ding-dong, ding-dong, ding-dong...
音でかい？お、いい感じ？
Is the volume too loud? Oh, feels good?
じゃ、一旦これでいくのじゃ！
Well, I'll go with this for now!
いつもの睡眠不足
My usual lack of sleep,
頭が痛くなっちゃうよ
makes my head start to hurt.
いつもの学校のいつもの教室
At school, in our usual classroom,
あのこは今日も元気だね
that girl is energetic again today.
すいみん すいみん すいみん不足
Sleep, sleep, I'm lacking sleep.
今日もいつもの睡眠不足
Today, it's my usual lack of sleep again,
体がほてってきちゃったよ
and my body is feeling all flushed.
たくさんやることあるのに
Even though I have so much to do,
頭がちっとも働かない
my brain just won't work at all.
あのこがわたしを悩ませる
That girl is troubling me,
わたしがあのこを悩ませる
and I am troubling that girl.
みんながみんなを悩ませる
Everyone is troubling everyone else,
みんなは心を痛めてる
and everyone's hearts are aching.
ああ 空はこんなに青いのに
Ah, even though the sky is so blue,
風はこんなに温かいのに
and the wind is so warm,
太陽はとっても明るいのに どうしてこんなに眠いの
and the sun is so bright, why am I so sleepy?
すいみん すいみん すいみん不足
Sleep, sleep, I'm lacking sleep.
今日もいつもの睡眠不足
Today, it's my usual lack of sleep again,
頭が痛くなっちゃうよ
making my head start to hurt.
いつもの学校のいつもの教室
At school, in our usual classroom,
あのこは今日も元気だね
that girl is energetic again today.
あのこがわたしを悩ませる
That girl is troubling me,
わたしがあのこを悩ませる
and I am troubling that girl.
みんながみんなを悩ませる
Everyone is troubling everyone else,
みんなは心を痛めてる
and everyone's hearts are aching.
ああ 空はこんなに青いのに
Ah, even though the sky is so blue,
風はこんなに温かいのに
and the wind is so warm,
太陽はとっても明るいのに どうしてこんなに眠いの
and the sun is so bright, why am I so sleepy?
すいみん すいみん すいみん不足
Sleep, sleep, I'm lacking sleep.
あのこがわたしを悩ませる
That girl is troubling me,
わたしがあのこを悩ませる
and I am troubling that girl.
みんながみんなを悩ませる
Everyone is troubling everyone else,
みんなは心を痛めてる
and everyone's hearts are aching.
ああ 空はこんなに青いのに
Ah, even though the sky is so blue,
風はこんなに温かいのに
and the wind is so warm,
太陽はとっても明るいのに どうしてこんなに眠いの
and the sun is so bright, why am I so sleepy?
ああ 空はこんなに青いのに
Ah, even though the sky is so blue,
風はこんなに温かいのに
and the wind is so warm,
太陽はとっても明るいのに どうしてこんなに
and the sun is so bright, why am I...
こんなに眠いの
...so sleepy?
すいみん すいみん すいみん不足
Sleep, sleep, I'm lacking sleep.
あー、緊張した！緊張したのじゃ！
Ah, I was so nervous! I was so nervous!
こんなにたくさんの人の前で歌ってめちゃくちゃ緊張したのじゃ！
Singing in front of so many people made me super nervous!
ちょっと、あの息が上がって心拍数が上がってるから、ちょっと落ち着いていいのじゃ？
Wait, my breathing is heavy and my heart rate is up, so can I calm down for a second?
ちょっと落ち着いていいのじゃ？ ちょっとお水飲むのじゃ？
Can I calm down a bit? Should I drink some water?
緊張したのじゃ…
I was so nervous...
キリトリだめだけど切り取りたいぐらい可愛いじゃあ、スクショオッケーじゃからスクショして配信のURLをツイートするのじゃ。
Clipping isn't allowed, but I'm cute enough that you'd want to clip me! Screenshots are fine, so take screenshots and tweet the stream URL!
メラちゃんの歌可愛すぎ笑ろたってつぶやいてじゃ。それはオッケーなのだじゃ。
Tweet things like \"Mela-chan's singing was way too cute, lol.\" That's totally okay!
あー、ちょっとお水飲むのじゃ。緊張したー！
Ah, I'm gonna drink some water. I was so nervous!
うん、スクショはオッケーなのだじゃ。
Yep, screenshots are totally okay.
はー、いっぱいひとがみてくれてるのじゃ。ドキドキするのじゃ。
Phew, so many people are watching. My heart is pounding.
なんでかみコップか？コップ洗うのめんどくさいからなのだじゃ。
Why a paper cup? Because washing dishes is a hassle!
かわいかった？かわいかったのじゃ？
Was I cute? Was I cute?
やったのじゃ！なんか、あのコメントでめちゃお湯湧きかいって言われてたのじゃ。お湯湧きかいじゃないのじゃ！
Yay! Also, someone in the comments said I sounded like hot spring steam! I am not hot spring steam!
ねぇ緊張しちゃうからさの
I'm super nervous, so...
あの、あんまりね、あの、リズムとかメロディーとかが細かくない曲を歌おうと思って。
Um, I thought I'd sing a song with less intricate rhythm and melody,
泳ぎ歌いって言われちゃったのじゃ。
and people told me I was 'floating-singing'.
ほっこりした？
Did it make you feel cozy?
ならよかったのじゃ。ならいいのじゃ。
Well, I'm glad. That's fine then.
うん。
Yep.
主らが父と母になっちゃうの？ わしでも400歳じゃよ！わし400歳じゃよ！
You guys are becoming my mom and dad? I'm 400 years old, you know! I'm 400 years old!
主らより年上じゃよ！およその主らより年上！うん。年上なのじゃ。
I'm older than you guys! Older than most of you! Yep, I'm older.
ふー、緊張したけど、頑張って歌っていくのじゃ。
Whew... I was so nervous, but I'll do my best and keep singing.
息が浅い。
My breathing is shallow.
深呼吸するのじゃ。主らもしていいよ。主らもわしと一緒に深呼吸していいよ。しよう、いくのじゃ。
Let's take a deep breath. You guys can do it too. You can breathe deep with me. Let's do it, here we go.
大緊張でしたのじゃ。
That was super stressful.
よいしょ、次の曲。
Alright, next song.
次はこちらの曲を歌いますのじゃ。ツイートした？ツイートありがとうなのだ！
Next, I'll sing this song. Did you tweet? Thanks for tweeting!
次はこちらの曲を歌いますのじゃ。ボカロ、ボカロが、やっぱわし好きだからさ、
Next, I'll sing this song. Vocaloid... I really love Vocaloid, so,
DECO*27さんのモニタリングを歌おうと思いますのじゃ。時代が急に来るのじゃ、確かに。
I thought I'd sing DECO*27's 'Monitoring'. Times change so suddenly, for real.
確かに。確かに。なんかできるだけいろんな人にわかる曲をちょっとずつ入れようと思って、初めての歌枠だし、初めての歌枠だし、うん。
For real. For real. I figured I'd include bits of songs that as many people as possible would know, since it's my first singing stream, my very first singing stream, yep.
そう、ベストフレンドじゃない方なのだ。
That's right, the non-best friend one.
こんばんはなのだ。うん。うん。歌おうと、思いますのじゃ。
Good evening. Yep. Yep. I think I'll sing it.
よいしょ。準備するのじゃ。よいしょ。えーっと、できたかな。よいしょ。よいしょ。
Alright. Getting ready. Alright. Um, is it ready? Alright. Alright.
モニタリングを歌うのじゃ。
I'll sing 'Monitoring'.
ねぇ あたし知ってるよ きみがひとり
Hey, I know that you're all alone,
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know, I know,
ビクンビクン震えてさ 声もだたもれなんだわ
twitching and shivering, your voice is shaking too.
正直にいっちゃいよ バレてんだし言っちゃいよ
Be honest, just admit it, you've been found out!
効いてんの 普通普通はずかしい みんな隠しているだけ
Are you listening? It's totally normal to be embarrassed, everyone's just hiding it,
ねぇ あたし知ってるよ きみがひとり
Hey, I know that you're all alone,
涙知ってるの 知ってるよ グスン グスン
I know your tears, I know, sniffling and sniffling,
へこんでさ 弱音吐きがちな イン ザ ナイト
feeling down, prone to complaining in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒こうす もっと泣いたって
Let's hang out together until morning, cry as much as you want,
なんとだって受け止めてあげる
I'll accept it no matter what.
もう我慢しないでいっぱい出してね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out.
MWAH! お願い きみが欲しいの 慰めなさして シェイク シェイク 愛の才能で
MWAH! Please, I want you. Let me comfort you, shake shake with the talent of love,
泣いてくれなきゃ 枯れてしまう 濡れていたい ねぇいいでしょ
if you don't cry, you'll wither away, I want to stay wet, hey, that's fine, right?
舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
Lick it up, I want to drink it all down.
MWAH! お願い きみが欲しいの 頼り散らして シック ラブ
MWAH! Please, I want you. Lean on me completely, sick love,
なんて最高ね 分けてくれなきゃ きみの痛い感じてたい
how amazing is that? If you don't share, I want to feel your pain.
ねぇいいでしょ 吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
Hey, that's fine, right? Sucking it up, I want to save you.
見たい 見たい 見たい 見たい 見たい 見たい 見たい 見たい 見たい
I want to see, see, see, see, see...
ねぇ あたし知ってるよ きみがひとり 悔しがってんの
Hey, I know that you're all alone, feeling frustrated.
知ってるよ ズキュン ズキュン 高まるじゃん
I know, zkyun zkyun, it's heightening,
きみを押すことはやめない
I won't stop pushing you.
ねぇ あたし知ってるよ きみはできる子 知ってるよ
Hey, I know that you're a capable kid, I know.
辛い時は 弱いくらいでちょうどいい あたしそれでも好きだよ
When times are tough, being a bit weak is just right, even so, I love you.
MWAH! お願い きみが欲しいの 名前を呼んでよ いったい会いに参上
MWAH! Please, I want you. Call my name, come to meet you in person,
きみはひとりだ だから歌う 「ひとりじゃない」
you're all alone, that's why I sing 'You're not alone'.
もういいでしょ ソロプレイはおしまいなんだってば きみが病めるときは あたし側にいるわ いつも見守っているのよ
That's enough, solo play is over. When you're feeling sick, I'll be right by your side, always watching over you.
いつも守っているわ そうよ怖くないのよ
I'm always protecting you. That's right, there's nothing to be afraid of.
アー MWAH! お願い きみが欲しいの
Ah, MWAH! Please, I want you.
慰めなさして シェイク シェイク 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you, shake shake, with the talent of love.
泣いてくれなきゃ 枯れてしまう 濡れたい体 ないんでしょ?
If you don't cry for me, I'll wither away. You want to get soaked, don't you?
舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
I want to lick it off and drink it all up, I'm telling you.
アー MWAH! お願い きみが欲しいの
Ah, MWAH! Please, I want you.
暴り散らして シックラブ なんて最高ね
Rampage around, sick love, how wonderful.
分けてくれなきゃ 君の痛い感じてたい
If you don't share it with me, I want to feel your pain.
覗いてたい 吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
I want to peek, suck it out, and save you, I'm telling you.
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみひとり涙してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're crying all by yourself.
グスン グスン 凹んでさん 弱音ヒトガラインじゃない 朝が来るまで一緒コス マタナイだって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
Sniffling and feeling down, don't go spilling your weaknesses. Until morning comes, let's cross it together, no matter how many times, I'll catch you.
もう我慢しないで 出ってば さあ
Don't hold back anymore, come out, now!
のじゃあ！
Nojaa!
モニタリングでしたのじゃ！
That was 'Monitoring'!
ちょっとまだ緊張して…
I'm still a bit nervous...
ちょっとまだ、まだまだ緊張してましたのじゃ！
I'm still, still so nervous, nojaa!
ありがとうなのじゃ！ 泳ぎから10年進んでた？
Thank you, nojaa! Have I advanced 10 years since swimming?
戦いの中で成長しているのじゃ！ 成長しているのじゃ！
I'm growing in the midst of battle, nojaa! I'm growing, nojaa!
うーん、恥ずかしいのじゃ。 お水飲むのじゃ。
Ugh, how embarrassing, nojaa. Time to drink some water, nojaa.
のじゃ！ のじゃ！ いっぱいのか人が見てくれてて嬉しいのじゃ！
Noja! Noja! I'm so happy so many people came to watch, nojaa!
わしの歌好きな人高評価をして欲しいのじゃ！ なぜならサラマンダーは高評価で育つ野じゃ！
If you like my singing, please give it a high rating, nojaa! Because salamanders grow on high ratings, nojaa!
いっぱい褒めてくれるなんかの初配信のな、初配信のあのわたわたの歌ってみたのも、なんかチラ見せ配信流した時も、なんかめちゃくちゃ褒めてくれてて、お主らコメントで…
You're praising me so much... For my first stream, that flustered cover song, and when I streamed a sneak peek, you guys praised me so much in the comments...
なんかかわいいと上手いしか言われてなくて、すごいね、すごいね、嬉しいのじゃ！ めっちゃ褒めてもらえる、めっちゃ褒めてもらえて嬉しいのじゃ！
You only said I was cute and good at singing, that's amazing, that's amazing, I'm so happy, nojaa! Getting praised so much, I'm so happy to be praised so much, nojaa!
なんでそんなかわいいか？ え、お主らがかわいいって言ってくれるからなのだじゃ！ 褒められたら褒めた分だけ育ちますのじゃ！
Why am I so cute? Eh, because you guys say I'm cute, nojaa! If you praise me, I grow as much as you praise me, nojaa!
やったのじゃ！ たくさんの褒め
Yay, nojaa! So much praise
はあ、ちょっとずつ緊張が減ってきているの感じるのじゃ。
Haa, I feel like my nervousness is gradually decreasing, nojaa.
もしボカロ大好きだから、今後もいっぱいボカロ歌枠で歌いたいなって思うし、ボカロの話、もっといっぱいしたいなって…うむ、うむ、のじゃ、のじゃ。
Since I love Vocaloid so much, I want to sing a lot of Vocaloid in singing streams in the future, and talk much more about Vocaloid... umu, umu, no ja, no ja.
いずれボカロ縛りもしたいのじゃ。 今日はですがいろんな歌を歌いたいと思ったので、よいしょ！
Eventually, I want to do a Vocaloid-only stream too, nojaa. But today, I wanted to sing various songs, so... yoisho!
わしのはアニソンも好きなのじゃ。 アニソンも大好きですのじゃ。 うん。 アニソン、ボカロも好きだけど…
I also like anime songs, nojaa. I love anime songs too, nojaa. Yeah. Anime songs, I like Vocaloid too, but...
結構アニソンとか作家さんの作る曲も好きで、わしのザックさんの曲すごい好きなんじゃが中二病でも声がしたいの曲なんじゃけど、スパークリングデイビリームっていう中二病でも恋がしたいの曲なのじゃ。
I also quite like anime songs and songs made by creators. I really like Zaq's songs, and there's this song 'Chuunibyou Demo Koi ga Shitai'—ah, 'Sparkling Daydream' is a song from Chuunibyou Demo Koi ga Shitai, nojaa.
すごい好きで中二病でも声がしたいの、作品は大体大体の曲がザックさんが手掛けてて、そう、特にわしのが一番お気に入りなのはアクロスラインテ曲なんじゃが…
I love it so much, most of the songs for Chuunibyou work are handled by Zaq, and yeah, especially my absolute favorite is a song called 'Across Line', nojaa...
今日はね、あの一期のオープニングのね、スパークリングデイリーモを。 そう、ハウリングの人、あのミオ先輩のハウリングを作ってるCGマンに響いてよ。 マイハウリングの作ってる方なのだじゃ。 うん。 すごい好きで、すごい好きだから歌っていこうと思うのじゃ。
Today, you know, for the first season's opening, 'Sparkling Daydream'... Yeah, the person who made Howling, Mio-senpai's Howling, made by CG Man, resonated with it. The person who made My Howling, nojaa. Yeah. I love it so much, so I'm going to sing it, nojaa.
そう、ぐるぐる回すやつ！ サビでぐるぐる回すやつのじゃ！ お主らサビでさ、ぐるぐるのコメントして…
Yeah, that thing where you spin around! The thing where you spin around in the chorus, nojaa! You guys, in the chorus, post spinning comments...
レッツゴー・ボース！ sparkling daydream
Let's go, boss! Sparkling daydream...
しばらく見つめ合ってから
After staring at each other for a while,
そらすまでに何を考えてたの？
what were you thinking before looking away?
気になる指先 覗かせた私を見て
Looking at my fingers peeking out with curiosity,
「どうしたの？」って聞いてくるの 待ってみるの
you ask me, "What's wrong?" while I wait for you.
ごまかしたあとの一人のときは
When I'm alone after brushing it off,
恥ずかしいから 聞かないでくれる？
it's so embarrassing, so please don't ask.
後に引けないほど惹かれ合う恋 もう始まってた
A love drawing us together so deeply we can't turn back had already begun.
夢ならたくさん見た 覚めたままでもまだ会いたい
I've dreamed so much, but even when awake, I still want to see you.
君がそうさせた 恋は欲張りだね 飛び跳ねそうな心の
You made me this way—love is so greedy, making my heart feel like it's leaping.
欲しままにゆこうよ 理想も妄想も現実も 全てを君を軸に回る新しい世界へ
Let's go as we desire! Ideals, delusions, and reality—all revolve around you into a brand new world.
Love's got me looking so crazy...
偶然聞こえた誰かの声が もう一度聞けたとき
When I heard someone's voice again by chance,
必然を信じた そんなとき 言葉に意味はなくて
I believed in destiny. At times like that, words lose their meaning;
体が動く 君を探して 痛みねじ伏せるように
my body moves, searching for you, as if to crush the pain.
現実逃避 でもそこにも君が現れて 臆病な私すら抱きしめてくれた
Escaping reality, but you appear there too, embracing even my cowardly self.
綺麗な空見上げて 君と描ける夢見るの
Looking up at the clear sky, I dream of the dreams I can weave with you.
明日もそうだよ 恋は終わらない 同じ星に生まれた
Tomorrow will be the same—love never ends. Born under the same star,
こんなチャンス他にない 運命と宿命が巡る 魔法にかかってるような輝く奇跡へ
there's no other chance like this. Toward a shining miracle, as if caught in the spell of circulating fate and destiny.
理想と妄想と現実とは違うようで同じなんだ
Ideals, delusions, and reality seem different, but they're the same.
形にはできないけれど どれも大切と悟るの
Though they can't take form, I realize each one is precious.
瞳が夜は忘れない 夢ならたくさん見た 覚めたままでもまだ会いたい
My eyes won't forget the night. I've dreamed so much, but even when awake, I still want to see you.
君がそうさせた 恋は欲張りだね
You made me this way—love is so greedy.
飛び跳ねそうな心の 欲しままにゆこうよ 理想も妄想も現実も 全てを君を軸に回る新しい世界へ
Let's go as our leaping hearts desire! Ideals, delusions, and reality—all revolve around you into a brand new world.
もり… 作曲家さん？ 作家さんでもあるんだけどさ
Mori... composer? She's also a writer, though.
そう、ザックさんの曲がめちゃくちゃ好きで、提供曲ほぼ全部追ってるぐらいね、めっっちゃ好きなのじゃが
Yeah, I love Zukka's songs so much, I follow almost all of the songs provided. I love them so much.
そうだからね、あれかも、めっっちゃ、めっっちゃ聴き…聴き込んでる。うん。めっっちゃ聴き込んでいるのじゃ。うん。
So yeah, maybe that's why... I listen to them so, so much. Yeah, I really listen to them on repeat.
から、すごい、すごい好きなのじゃ。うん。大好きな作家さんなのですのじゃ。うん。
So, I love them so, so much. Yeah, they're my favorite composer/writer. Yeah.
提供もめちゃくちゃいい。中二病でも声がしたいの、あの曲の「アクロスザライン」って曲がめちゃくちゃ好きで、いつか歌枠で歌いたいのじゃ。めっっちゃ好きなのじゃ。うん。
The provided songs are also amazing. I love "Across the Line" from Chuunibyou so much, and I want to sing it in a stream someday.
そうそう、クラスルームとかそういう日常の曲とかね、うん、そうそうそうそう。ソラオトとかね、そう。そうそうそうそう、なのじゃ、なのじゃ。うん。
Yeah, yeah, Classroom and other everyday songs, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Soraoto, too, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
え、なんか歌めちゃくちゃ褒めてもらえるけど、歌そんなに、歌そんなに自信なくて、このライブ入る前にめちゃくちゃ練習して、めちゃくちゃ練習したから、すごい嬉しいのじゃ。うん。
Um, people praise my singing so much, but I wasn't very confident in my singing, and I practiced so much before this live stream, and I'm so happy.
この後ろが今上げてくれてる曲大体全部知ってんのじゃ。大体全部知ってんのじゃ。ソウルフニアもトゥッティじゃの。
Almost all the songs playing behind me right now, I know them. I know almost all of them. Soulphinia and Tutti, right?
大体全部知ってんのじゃ。いつか歌いたいのだじゃ。めちゃくちゃ褒められって…すごい練習したのじゃ！うん。なのじゃ。嬉しいのですのじゃ。ありがとなのじゃ。
I know almost all of them. I want to sing them someday. I'm being praised so much... I practiced so hard! Yeah. I'm so happy. Thank you.
緊張が溶けてきた〜。緊張溶けてきた。日常おもろいよね。うん。お水入れてきていい？
My tension is melting away~. My tension has melted away. Nichijou is interesting, right? Yeah. Can I go get some water?
よいしょ。よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、のじゃ。のじゃ。
Heave-ho. Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho...
ウォーターサーバーをね、横に置いてるの。配信中にね、いつでもね、お水を撮れるようにね、ウォーターサーバーをね、横にある、うん、置いてるのじゃ。うん。のじゃ。
I have a water dispenser next to me. During the stream, so I can get water anytime, I have a water dispenser right next to me, yeah.
次何歌おうとしたんだっけ。シセードリミットを…ちらちらちらちらちら。フォニイ！
What was I going to sing next? Shiseido Limit... glance, glance, glance. Phony!
そうじゃった、そうじゃった。やはりね、好きなボカロPさんはツミキさんって言ってるので、ツミキさんの曲をご用意してきましたのじゃ。いつかサカクラカーストの曲も歌いたいのじゃ。うん。
That's right, that's right. As expected, since my favorite Vocaloid producer is Tsumiki, I prepared one of Tsumiki's songs.
フォニイ、そう。え、お面つけて歌っちゃおうかな、フォニイだし。お面つけて歌っちゃおうかな。フォニイお面の曲じゃし。MVがね。
Phony, yeah. Um, maybe I'll sing it wearing a mask, since it's Phony. Maybe I'll sing it wearing a mask. Phony is a masked song, right?
ぼかろ好きなのじゃ。ぼかろ好きなのじゃ。前回のぼかろも見てたのじゃ。うん。ぼかろ好きなのじゃ。うん。お面つけて歌っちゃおう。のじゃ。のじゃのじゃ。
I love Vocaloid. I love Vocaloid. I saw the previous Vocaloid one too. Yeah. I love Vocaloid. Yeah. Let's sing wearing a mask. Yeah.
雰囲気出るのじゃ。かっこいいお面。かっこいいお面なのじゃ。うん。うん。よし。
It gives off the vibe. A cool mask. A cool mask, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Alright.
いや難しいんだよな。わしねボカロ大好きなんじゃが、ボカロ大好きなんじゃがボカロってね、いかんせんね、あのやっぱね、早いしね、高いしね、むずいから上手に歌えるかがちょっと不安なのだが。
Man, it's so difficult. I love Vocaloid so much, but Vocaloid is fast, high, and hard, so I'm a bit nervous about whether I can sing it well.
不安なのだが、頑張るのじゃ。緊張も溶けてきたことだし、フォニイ歌うのじゃ！うん。いくのじゃ。のじゃ。のじゃ。
I'm nervous, but I'll do my best. My tension has melted away, so I'm going to sing Phony! Yeah. Let's go. Yeah.
この世で花より綺麗な花は無いわ
There is no flower prettier than a flower in this world.
なぜならば全ては嘘で作られている
Because everything is made of lies,
antipathy world
絶望の雨はあたちの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pierces my umbrella,
湿らす前髪と心の裏面 煩わしいわ
dampening my bangs and the reverse side of my heart—how annoying.
いつしか古事の葉はとにかれ切って
Before I knew it, the leaves of antiquity were withered away,
ことの実があたしに触れている
and the fruit of words touches me.
鏡に映り嘘を描いて
Drawing lies reflected in the mirror,
自らを失ったメイク
make-up that lost its true self.
パッパパラッパ なぞなぞ 数えて 遊びましょう
Counting riddles, pa-pa-pa-ra-pa, let's play!
タッタタラタッタラタッタ
Ta-ta-ta-ra-ta-ta-ra-ta-ta
何故何故何故が 踊っているでしょう
Why, oh why is it dancing here?
簡単なことも解からないわ あたしって何だっけ
I don't even understand simple things—what am I again?
それすら夜の手に把らされて
Even that was caught in the hands of night,
愛のように消える
vanishing like love.
さよならも言えぬまま泣いた フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, Phony, crying without even being able to say goodbye.
嘘に絡まっている あたしはフォニイ
Tangled in lies, I am a phony.
antipathy world
何時しか其の香が いなに混り合って
Before long, those scents blended together,
色の目があなたを絶えている
and the colored eyes endured you.
鏡に映るあたしを描いて
Drawing myself reflected in the mirror,
誰しもう見間違えたフェイク
a fake that anyone would mistake.
どうして愛なんてものに群がり
Why do people swarm around love
それを無視して生きるのだ
and live by ignoring it?
今日も泳いでいるのさ 電車が通り去っていく
Today too, I'm swimming as trains pass by.
おどり明かせよ パッパパラッパ
Dance the night away, pa-pa-pa-ra-pa!
なぞなぞ 魂て歌いましょう
Let's sing while tricking our souls with riddles.
タッタタラタッタラタッタ
Ta-ta-ta-ra-ta-ta-ra-ta-ta
なぜなぜ ここが痛むのでしょう
Why, oh why does it hurt right here?
散々な日々は変わらないわ
Disastrous days never change.
絶望の雨は止まないわ
The rain of despair never stops.
さよならも言えぬまま泣いた フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, Phony, crying without even being able to say goodbye.
嘘に絡まっている あたしはフォニイ
Tangled in lies, I am a phony.
簡単なことも解からないわ
I don't even understand simple things—
あたしって何だっけ それすら夜の手に把らされて
what was I again? Even that was caught in the hands of night,
愛のように消える さよならも言えぬまま泣いた
vanishing like love, crying without even being able to say goodbye.
フォニイ フォニイ 嘘に絡まっている
Phony, Phony, tangled in lies—
あたしはフォニイ 遠花火だけが知っている
I am a phony, known only by distant fireworks.
秘密のフォニイ
A secret phony.
フォニイでしたのいじゃー
That was "Phony," Noija!
かっこよかったのいじゃ？ お面つけたのいじゃ。
Was it cool? I put on a mask.
いい感じ？ 顔かっこいい？ やったのいじゃ！
Does it look good? Is my face cool? Yay!
え、大満足？ ベタ褒め？
Eh, totally satisfied? Showered with praise?
ベタベタ褒め褒めじゃない？ ベタベタ褒め褒めなのいじゃ！やったのいじゃ！
Isn't that praise upon praise? It's praise upon praise, yay!
え、なんか歌った歌ってこんなに褒められて嬉しいのいじゃ。
Eh, I'm so happy to be praised this much for singing a song.
お主ら、いつか、わしがソロライブできることになったら聞きに来てね！聞きに来て欲しいのいじゃ。
You guys, someday when I'm able to hold a solo live, come listen! I want you to come listen.
とっても嬉しいから、うん、とっても嬉しいからその時は聞きに来て欲しいのいじゃ。
I'd be so happy, yeah, so please come listen when that time comes.
のいじゃ。ありがとうなのいじゃ！やったのいじゃ！
Noija. Thank you so much, Noija! Yay, Noija!
はぁー、嬉しいのいじゃ。
Ahh, I'm so happy.
ツミキさんの曲めっちゃ好き！ボカロも好きだし、提供曲も好きだし、
I love Tsumiki's songs so much! I love Vocaloid, I love the songs provided,
ノーメロとかも好きだし、今後いろんな曲を歌いたいなって思うのいじゃ。
I love "No Melo" and stuff, and I think I want to sing various songs in the future.
うん、いろんなの歌いたいなあって、うん。
Yeah, I want to sing all kinds of things, yeah.
のいじゃ、のいじゃ。
Noija, Noija.
いや、緊張だいぶ落ち着いてきたのいじゃ、最初最初ガチガチだったから。
Man, my nervousness has calmed down quite a bit, since I was super stiff at first.
超学生姫好きになったのボカロから？
Did you start liking Chogakusei-hime from Vocaloid?
そう、その、超学生姫は、あの、始まる前に作品が始まる前に歌ってみた、その、早見沙織さんとかの、声優さんのボカロ曲歌ってみたとかが上がってたじゃろ？
Right, Chogakusei-hime had cover songs of Vocaloid tracks by voice actresses like Saori Hayami uploaded before works started, right?
それで超学生姫を知って、あぁ、なんかこういうのあるのかと思って、見よ、と思って見たら、好きになったのじゃ。
That's how I found out about Chogakusei-hime, thought "Oh, they have stuff like this," checked it out, and came to love it.
あー、落ち着いてきたのいじゃ。
Ahh, I've calmed down.
始まったときガチでガチガチ、ガチガチだったのいじゃ。
When it started, I was seriously stiff, completely stiff.
ホロライブの曲も歌わないかな？え、最後までいったらなんか聴けちゃうんじゃないかなのいじゃ？
Won't you sing Hololive songs too? Eh, if we go all the way to the end, maybe we can hear Hololive songs?
最後までいったらもしかしてホロライブの歌も聴けちゃうかも、聴けちゃうか...
If we go all the way, maybe we can even hear Hololive songs, can we...
かもしれないのじゃ
Maybe...
最後までいるといいことがある気がするのじゃ。
I feel like something good will happen if you stay until the end.
声震えてた。
My voice was trembling.
睡眠不足歌ってる時、本当に声めっちゃ震えてたのじゃ、ガチガチ。
When I sang 'Suimin Busoku', my voice was really shaking, totally jittery.
あの今来たお主らは、あのアーカイブで
For those of you who just came, in the archive—
アーカイブでわしの
in the archive, my...
わしのガチガチの睡眠不足聞いてほしい。
please listen to my super shaky 'Suimin Busoku'.
ガチでもめっちゃ緊張した、めっちゃ緊張したのじゃん。
Seriously, I was so nervous, I was super nervous.
うん、めっちゃ緊張してたのじゃ。
Yeah, I was super nervous.
プルプルだった、プルプルじゃった。
I was all jittery, totally jittery.
でも、あの絶対最初緊張するかなって思って、絶対最初緊張するかなって思ったから、
But, thinking I'd definitely be nervous at first, since I thought I'd definitely be nervous at first,
あの、最初はね、緊張しても歌える曲をね持ってきたのじゃ。
um, at first, I brought songs I could sing even if I was nervous.
何時までか？あと何曲かの、何曲じゃったっけ？
Until what time? How many more songs, how many was it again?
7、2、3？ちょっと忘れちゃった。
7, 2, 3? I kinda forgot.
忘れちゃったけど、忘れちゃったけど
I forgot, but I forgot, but
ちょっと待っての、ちょっと待っての。
hold on, hold on.
あとね、今フォニイまで歌ったでしょ、あと3曲！
And hey, I sang up to 'Phyny' just now, 3 more songs!
今日はね、あと3曲ね歌おうと思ってね、来たのじゃ。
Today, you know, I came planning to sing 3 more songs.
うん、あと3曲歌わせていただきますのじゃ。
Yep, I'll let you hear 3 more songs.
あの、きょ、今週の日曜日、日曜日にも歌枠があるから
Um, tod-, this Sunday, since there's a singing stream on Sunday too,
日曜日も歌枠があるから、だから、あの喉をね
since there's a singing stream on Sunday too, so, you know, sparing my throat
労わりつつ歌おうと思うのじゃ。アンコールはないのじゃ。
I plan to sing while taking care of it. There's no encore.
次の曲はね
The next song is
次もアニソンなのじゃ、よいしょ。ででーん！
the next one is also an anime song, here we go. Tada!
「アイを歌えって曲を次は歌おうかなって思っておって
I thought about singing the song 'Ai wo Utae' next,
この曲アニソンなんじゃが、あの物語シリーズ？
this song is an anime song, but, you know, the Monogatari series?
作曲がね、作曲がじんさんなんじゃよ。
The composer, you know, the composer is Jin-san.
じんさんってボカロPのさ、そのカゲプロとか作っていらっしゃるさ
Jin-san is a Vocaloid producer who makes Kagepro and stuff, right?
そう、じんさんが作曲なんじゃよ。そう。
Right, Jin-san composed it. Exactly.
から、アニソンも好きだしボカロも好きだしってわしにとってすっごい好き、すっごい好きな曲なのじゃ。
So, since I love both anime songs and Vocaloid, to me it's a super loved, super loved song.
そうですのじゃ。
That's right.
よし、歌っちゃおっかな。
Alright, shall I go ahead and sing it?
よいしょ、よいしょのじゃ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
よし！「アイを歌え」、物語シリーズのじんさんの曲、歌っちゃいますのじゃ、のじゃ。
Alright! 'Ai wo Utae', from the Monogatari series, Jin-san's song, I'm gonna sing it!
心臓に合わせて
Aligning with my heartbeat,
本当の気持ちを自分らしくさ 話そう
let's talk about our true feelings, as ourselves.
平凡な金曜日 落ち込んだ毎日は
An ordinary Friday, every depressed day
言い訳と後悔の 連続
is a succession of excuses and regrets.
作戦を考えて 「この気持ちとやって」
Thinking of a strategy, saying 'Deal with this feeling'
希望叶って 今日も終わる
hoping for the best, today ends as well.
君の目が泳いだら 不安でしょうがないんだよ
When your eyes waver, I can't help feeling anxious,
「嫉妬しちゃう 嫌い嫌い」って 意気込んで 堪らないんだ
'I get jealous, I hate it, I hate it,' brimming over, I can't stand it.
ホントはね ずっと君と二人だけが良かったんだ
The truth is, I always wanted it to be just the two of us.
純粋なアイのコトバ 笑わないでよ ねえ
Pure words of love, don't laugh, hey.
きっとまたそんな君を 「諦めてやるもんか」って
I'm sure I'll give up on giving up on you like that,
必死に答えを探す バカみたいだね はあ
desperately searching for an answer, how foolish, ah.
余裕なんてないんだよ 喉元まで出かかってた
I have no composure, it was right up to my throat,
溜め息を飲み込んで リセットしよう
swallowing down a sigh, let's reset.
出来合いの言葉で 飾った想いなんて 2パーセントも伝わらない
Feelings dressed up in ready-made words won't convey even 2 percent.
ホントの心を 言葉にしよう 「気取ってないか」って
Let's put our true heart into words, wondering 'Am I putting on airs?'
ねぇ いつもの道
Hey, on our usual road,
合わす歩幅 掠れた声の中
matching strides amidst a hoarse voice,
胸のテンポが少し駆け抜けて
my heartbeat races a little faster.
こんな気持ち なんて名前？
What is this feeling called?
まだまだこれじゃ追い付かないよ
This still isn't enough to catch up to you.
胸に気持ちが溢れきちゃって
My feelings overflowed from my chest,
全然こんなの慣れないな この意味分かって
I'm not used to this at all—please understand what this means.
ずっと続く「好き」を スッと言えたなら
If I could smoothly say the "I love you" that keeps going,
君に届くかな 届くように 伝うこの鼓動が
would it reach you? So that it reaches you, this beating pulse
バレないうちに 声に乗せて、言いたいよ
I want to put into my voice and say before it's found out.
止めどない息 繰り返しでも ほら「まだまだ」って立ってるでしょ？
Even with endless breath repeated, look, I'm still standing, right?
あの日あの時に 何かが生まれたから
Because on that day, at that time, something was born,
きっとまた辛いことだって あるの当然
it's only natural that painful things will happen again.
あのね、ホントはね 涙を隠しながら
You know, honestly, while hiding my tears,
絶対に諦めないように 息を吸い込む
I draw in a breath so as never to give up.
「ホントはね ずっとずっと 言えなくて寂しかったんだ」
"Honestly, I've always been lonely because I couldn't say it."
心臓がエールを送る このままホントだよ
My heart sends me cheers—this is truly how it is.
ずっとずっと 二人だけでいたかったんだ
I've always wanted to be just the two of us.
純粋なアイのコトバ やっと言えたね
I was finally able to say those pure words of love.
最初からこの気持ちが 君だけに向いてるだって
That right from the start, these feelings have been turned only toward you.
真剣な恋の行方 どうなるんだろうね
Where will this serious romance lead?
目と目を合わせたら 怖がらずに ほら 話してみよう
If our eyes meet, without being scared, come on, let's talk.
自分だけの心を
With just my own heart.
のじゃー！
Noja!
のじゃ。
Noja.
なんでもしてその声。なんでも知らないのじゃ。
Whatever that voice is. I don't know anything about it.
知ってることだけしか知らないのじゃ。
I only know the things I actually know.
ネットミームはあんまり詳しくありませんのじゃ。
I'm not very familiar with internet memes.
でも、あの…知ってるミームがあるといたくなっちゃいますのじゃ。
But, um... when there's a meme I know, I can't help wanting to say it.
のじゃ。
Noja.
アイを歌えでしたー！のじゃー！
That was 'Ai o Utae'! Noja!
お歌は練習中だけど、いっぱい褒めてもらえて嬉しいですのじゃ。
I'm still practicing my singing, but I'm so happy to get so much praise!
噛みました？噛みまみたのじゃー！
Did I stumble? I totally mumbled it, noja!
のじゃ。
Noja.
のじゃ。いっぱい褒められている。
Noja. I'm being praised so much.
いっぱい褒められているー！のじゃ。
I'm being praised so much! Noja.
やったのじゃ。
We did it, noja.
江戸時代に流行った曲も聞きたい。
I'd love to hear songs popular in the Edo period too.
わし現代っ子だから江戸時代もずっと山引きの時以外は火事があるときは街に降りて手伝ってたけど、火事がないときは基本山に降りてましたのじゃ。
I'm a modern kid, so back in the Edo period whenever there wasn't a mountain fire, if there was a fire I'd go down to town to help, but when there wasn't, I basically hung out in the mountains, noja.
つづりが褒めてくれてる。ありがとうなのじゃ。
Tsuzuri is praising me. Thank you, noja.
のじゃ。デイズだっての聞きたい。目隠しティアーズなのだ。いつか歌いたいのだ。
Noja. I want to hear 'Days' too. And 'Mekakushi Tears'. I want to sing them someday.
のじゃ。いっぱいの人間が見てくれてて嬉しいのじゃ。やったのじゃ。
Noja. I'm so happy so many people are watching. Yay, noja.
育ちの親から流行りの曲知ったの？んー曲はね、インターネットで知ったのじゃ。
Did I learn trendy songs from my adoptive parents? Hmm, I learned songs on the internet, noja.
曲はインターネットで知ったのじゃ。ボカロが大好きなのじゃ。楽器弾けないのじゃ。
I learned songs on the internet, noja. I love Vocaloid, noja. I can't play instruments.
はげプロもいつか歌いたいのだ。まあまお主らお主ら、そうそうせかすでない、せかすでない。
I want to sing Hage Pro someday too. Now now, you guys, don't rush me, don't rush me.
まだ初めての歌枠なんだから。まだ初めてなんだから。ちょっとずつちょっとずつですのじゃ。
This is still my very first singing stream. Since it's still my first, little by little, noja.
噛んじゃった。ちょっとずつですのじゃ。
I stumbled. Little by little, noja.
日曜日に歌枠あるから！日曜日にも歌枠ありますのじゃ。始まったらそれ告知するのじゃ。
There's a singing stream on Sunday! There'll be one on Sunday too, noja. I'll announce it when it starts.
まあまあまあせかすでない。いつかネ！いつか歌うからね！まだまだですのじゃ。まだ初回ですのじゃ。
Now, now, don't rush me. Someday, you know! I'll sing it someday! I still have a long way to go, noja. It's still my first time, noja.
じゃあ次の曲歌っちゃおうと思うんじゃが、よし。
Well, I think I'll sing the next song, alright.
じゃあ、じゃあ…
Now, now...
わしが、わしがあのホロライブの…
I, I was in Hololive's...
わしがホロライブの、あのオーディションの時に送った曲…
The song I sent for Hololive's audition...
わしがホロライブのオーディションで、あの、この曲が好きなんですよって話をね、長々と語った、
The song I talked about at length during the Hololive audition,
熱く語った曲。すごく好きな曲なんじゃが、すごい好きな曲なんだけど、
talking passionately about how much I love this song.
わしが好きなのってカフさんが歌うトウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴじゃから、
what I love is Kaf-san's version of "Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous",
そう、ボーカルがカフの、カフさんのトウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴが好きじゃから、自分で歌うといまいち物足りねえのじゃ。正直。
so when I sing it myself, it's somehow not satisfying enough. Honestly.
正直ね、物足りない。正直物足りないけど、大好きじゃから、大好きじゃから歌わせていただきますのじゃ。うん。
Honestly, it's not enough. But because I love it so much, I'll let myself sing it.
そう、あるあるなのじゃ。好きなアーティストのあるある。カラオケのあるあるなのじゃ。うん。ま、でも、できる限り、できる限り頑張って歌わせていただきたいなと思うのじゃ。うん。
Yeah, it's a common thing. A common thing for favorite artists. Karaoke common sense.
じゃあお主に聞いてもらっちゃおうかな。聞いてもらっちゃおうかな。よっこらしょ。
Well then, I'll have you listen to it. Have you listen to it. Here we go.
それでは聞いてください。よっこらしょ。
Now then, please listen. Here we go.
トウキョウ…（エコをつけるのありがとうしてくれて）トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ！毎回エコを忘れるのじゃ。
Tokyo... (Thanks for adding the echo) Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous! I always forget the echo.
電波テンポアップして 絶賛感電中！
Tempo ramping up, currently getting electrified!
あなたにも 忘れたいこと
Is there something you too want to forget,
悲しいこと あるのかしらね
something sad you want to leave behind?
知らない映画なのに涙を流すのは ドラマチックが足りないからよ
Crying over a movie you don't even know must be because you lack drama.
そんな愚にも付かないこと くだらないこと
Such pointless, trivial things,
考えばっかりね 雨が上がれば愛もそのユーゴがオモウ
thinking about them all the time. When the rain clears, love...
誰かのものになるのでしょう 嘘っぱちのファンデーションも全部
will probably belong to someone else. All these fake foundations
今夜のためよ なのに一体全体どうして
are for tonight. Yet why on earth
一体どうしてなずなず張ってな
why, why are you lingering like this?
不安定なカンテラ どこまで行くの
Unstable lantern, how far will you go?
あなた一切合切放り出してもわ 冗談じゃないないわ
Even if you throw everything of yours away, it's no joke at all.
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ その時が来たってどうにもなんないぜ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous, even if that time comes, nothing can be done!
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ あたしをさあ捕まえて今テイコミー
Ambiguous truths just turn into melancholy; catch me now, take me!
はあ ちゃっちゃとおかしな法度ばかりで 食指が動くともしないわ
Ah, with all these weird taboos, my appetite won't even budge.
実際の無い感情放っておいたって 策略なんてありゃせぬのに なぜ
Leaving unreal emotions unattended, even though there are no schemes, why?
あたしのハートなる気質もじっと喰らって取り繕ってはダーティ
Even my heart-like temperament, swallowed and patched up, is dirty.
年がら年中リップサービス どんがらがっしゃんフィールガールは涙の目にも鬼に
Year-round lip service, crash-bang feel girl is a demon even in tears.
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいで あなたの話は一向に聞き取れない
Now, because of the music in my head, I can't catch a single word you're saying.
少しはまっとうなこと言っていいえ 周り出すターンテーブル
Say something a bit more sensible—no, the turntable starts spinning.
だって一体全体どうしてねえ全部忘れさせいてよ
Yet why on earth, make me forget everything!
不安定なカンテラ 消えないまんまで
Unstable lantern, remaining unextinguished.
あなた一切合切放り出してもわ
Even if you throw everything of yours away,
冗談じゃないないわ
it's no joke at all.
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ その時が来たってどうにもなんないぜ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous, even if that time comes, nothing can be done!
不甲斐ないわ感情なんてランドリーで落とすだけ
Worthless emotions just washed in the laundry;
あたしと確かめ合ってイエローマジック
confirming with me, yellow magic.
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ その時が来たってどうにもなんないぜ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous, even if that time comes, nothing can be done!
大人なんてメランコリーイガスルだけ
It's a melancholy world...
あたしもさっかさらって今手こみ、イエス!
And I'm gonna run away and take it on, yes!
じゃーん!
Ta-da!
東京シャンディランデヴでしたのじゃ。
That was "Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous"!
わ、緊張が解けた頃に歌えばよかった!
Well, I wish I'd sung it when the nerves had worn off, haha!
どうじゃった?
How was it?
かっこいいが勝つ? え、かっこよかったかのえ?
Was it cool? Did it sound cool?
そうかの。
So, yeah.
うん、すごい好きな曲だからね、いっぱい聴いてますのじゃ。
It's a song I really love, so I listen to it a lot, you know?
いっぱい聴いてますのじゃ。
I listen to it a lot, you know.
え、なんかめっっちゃ褒められちゃう。
Ah, wait, I'm getting praised so much!
めっちゃ褒められるのじゃー!
I'm getting praised so much, you know!
嬉しいのじゃ、ありがとなのじゃー!
I'm so happy, thank you so much, you know!
やったのじゃー!
Yay, you know!
そして、東京シャンディランデヴを歌ったということは
And since I sang "Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous,"
残りあと1曲になっちゃったのじゃー!
That means there's only one song left, you know!
うん。
Yeah.
最後の曲ですのじゃ!
It's the last song, you know!
最後の曲は、やっぱホロライブの曲をせっかくだし歌いたいなって思ってて、
The last song is... since it's a Hololive song, I really wanted to sing one, you know?
ホロライブの曲を歌いたいなって思ってて、
I've been thinking, "I really want to sing a Hololive song!"
あの、その前に、1個、1個だけおぬしらに言いたいことがあるんだよ。言いたいことがあるんだよ。
And before that, there's just one thing I really want to say to you all!
言いたいことが1個だけあるのじゃー!
There's just one thing I want to tell you, you know!
あそびまわりたい!デビュー記念歌わクリレーが10月の4日日曜日の20時から行われますのじゃー!
The "Asobi Mawaritai! Debut Kinen Utawakurirei" will be held on Sunday, October 4th, at 8:00 PM, you know!
歌配信するのじゃ。あそびまわりたいで歌わクリレーをしますのじゃー!
I'll be doing a singing stream, you know! We'll be doing the "Asobi Mawaritai" singing relay!
だから、めらちゃんこれ今日絶対歌うと思ってたのに歌わなかったんだよなって曲あるじゃろ。
You know how sometimes you think, "Mela-chan, I'm definitely going to sing this today," but then there's that one song you end up not singing?
正直めらちゃん絶対これ歌うだろと思ってた曲あるじゃろ。
Honestly, there are some songs you think, "Mela-chan is definitely going to sing that!"
今日聴けなかったけど、あれ歌うと持ってんだよなって曲が思い浮かば、思い当たるおぬしら、あそびまわりたいデビュー記念歌わクリレーに来るのじゃ。
Well, even though I didn't get to sing it today, I was thinking, "I want to sing it for the debut singing relay!"
デビュー記念歌わクリレーで撮って置いてるのじゃ。うん、撮って置いたのじゃ。うん。
I've already got it saved for the debut singing relay! Yeah, I've got it saved, you know! Yeah.
なので、またねこれもね、Twitterの方で、あの、即出しをね、出すので、10月の4日の20時から開けといてほしいのじゃ。4人で歌わクリレーをしたあとに最後に4人でコラボで歌ったりしちゃおうかなって思っているので、楽しみにしていてほしいのじゃー!
So, like I said, we'll also be doing a spoiler section on Twitter for this! It'll be open starting October 4th at 8:00 PM, after the four of us finish the singing relay, and then we're planning to do a four-person collab stream to sing together, so I hope you're looking forward to it, you know!
もうすぐ1時間、いい時間。いい時間になってきたのじゃ。
It's almost an hour—a good time. It's getting to be a good time, you know.
いい時間になってきたから、ちょっとお水をいれて、お水をいれてから、最後の曲を歌うのじゃ。よいしょ。
It's getting to be a good time, so I'll drink some water. After drinking water, I'll sing the last song, okay? Here we go.
1枠どれぐらい?なんか20分ぐらいだった気がする。ごめん、ちゃんとちゃんと覚えてないのじゃ。
How long was that first block? About 20 minutes, I think? I don't really remember clearly, you know.
なんかちょっと、ちょっとずつ、ちょっと、ちょっとずつだった気がする。
It feels like it was just a little, little bit each time.
ごめん、確定なんか忘れちゃった。忘れちゃったのじゃ。
Oops, I forgot the confirmation! I forgot it, you know.
あめなめっちゃを、あめなめっちゃを。よいしょ、よいしょ。うんうんうん。あめなめっちゃを。
Ame Nametja... Ame Nametja... Yeah, yeah, yeah. Ame Nametja...
おぬしら最後何歌うと思う?
What do you think Holosr's last song will be?
何が聴きたい?
What do you want to hear?
おぬしらホロライブの曲で、わしがはじめての歌わくね。何聴きたい?
It's Holosr's song, and it's my very first singing stream, you know!
まあSSSもわかるのじゃ。気持ちは。
I can tell even from the SSS, I know how you're feeling, you know!
わかりますのじゃ。
You know it, right?
わしが、ホロライブに
It's because I'm on Hololive...
あ、るきっかげになった曲がございますのじゃ。
Ah, there's a song that became the catalyst for me.
わしが、このライブに…このライブ言えるかな？
I wonder if I can say "holo live" at the end of this stream...
歌枠の最後にこのライブ言えるか歌い出したら超おもろいけどね。
It'd be super funny if I started singing it at the very end.
ほら、みんなでって歌い出したら超おもろいけどね。
If I started singing "Hora, minna de", it'd be super funny.
ということで最後の曲、最後の曲は『Our Bright Parade』歌わせていただこうと…
And so, for the final song... The final song, I'd like to sing "Our Bright Parade"...
歌わせていただこうと、おもまいりますのじゃ。
I thought I'd like to sing it.
初配信でもお伝えした通り、あの、わし、Kemuさんが好きで、ボカロピー…ボカロがっすごい好きで、ボカロPさんの提供曲を聞くのがすごい好きなんじゃが、
As I mentioned in my debut stream, I really love Kemu-san, and Vocaloid... I love Vocaloid so much, and I really love listening to songs provided by Vocaloid producers.
そのの中でも、そのKemuさんっていうね、ボカロPさんがいらっしゃって、堀江晶太さんっていう方がいらっしゃるんじゃが、
Among them, there's a Vocaloid producer named Kemu-san, and there's also someone named Shota Horie.
その堀江晶太さんの提供曲をね、探っていた時期があったのじゃ。
There was a time when I was searching for songs provided by Shota Horie.
探っていた時に、その曲の中に『Our Bright Parade』っていう曲があって、
When I was searching, among those songs was one called "Our Bright Parade".
そう、その曲を見つけて、聞いたときに、涙が出たのじゃ。
That's right, when I found that song and listened to it, tears came out.
この曲に呼ばれたって、思ったのじゃ。
I thought, "I've been called by this song."
だから、すごい、わしにとって思い出がある曲を初めての歌枠で歌わせていただこうと思って、
That's why I thought I wanted to sing such a memorable song for me in my very first singing stream,
歌わせていただきたいと思ったのじゃ。大切な曲なのじゃ。
and I wanted to sing it. It's a precious song.
いい曲いっぱいあるんじゃけど、やっぱね、思い出補正みたいなのもあって、
There are so many good songs, but of course, there's also memory bias,
そう、いい曲いっぱいあるけど、中でも、中でも好きな曲なのじゃ。
yeah, there are lots of good songs, but among them, it's one of my favorites.
ちょっと緊張するんじゃが、緊張するんだが、じゃが、歌わせていただくのじゃ。
I'm a bit nervous, but... I'm going to sing it.
お主らは、お主らは高評価ボタンをして応援してほしいですのじゃ。頑張れ、まのじゃ。
And you guys, I'd appreciate it if you hit the like button and support me. Do your best, Meno-ja!
それでは、歌っちゃおうかな。
Well then, shall I sing it?
のじゃ。それでは、歌わせていただきますのじゃ。
No-ja. Well then, I will sing it for you.
パレード、パレード、パレード！
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
Shining brightly!
呼び合う声を合図に
With our calling voices as the signal,
パレード、パレード、パレード！
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探しに行く
We go to search for it.
スタートは何度だって
The start is however many times it takes.
ただ独り言を呟った
I just muttered to myself,
ただ始まりたくて走った
I ran just because I wanted it to begin.
遠く暗がりにとまった
Stopped far away in the darkness.
それは眩し過ぎた名前
That was a name that shone too brightly.
それは優し過ぎる思い出もっと
That was a memory far too gentle—even more,
近づけと手を伸ばした
I stretched out my hand, wanting to get closer.
思いがけず結び合った
We unexpectedly bound together.
ほら 今 迷子は僕らになった
Look, now we've become lost children together.
パレード、パレード、パレード！輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! Shining brightly,
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring along both frustration and affection.
風夢跳ね 飛び立てるさ
Wind, leap in dreams, you can take flight.
ささやかな祈りは 光
A modest prayer is the light.
終わりなき兆し 君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
An endless sign—discovering you, I can puff out my chest with pride.
ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade, Parade!
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade, Parade, Parade!
まだ頼りない予感を
A still unreliable premonition...
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんてないよ
Let's sing it, there's nothing to be ashamed of.
誰も解けない イマジナリー
An imaginary that no one can solve.
いつかまた会える おまじない
A spell to meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
The story that began from zero that day.
数え切れない 言の葉 数えるような想いじゃないさ
It's not about counting countless words.
ほら 今 僕らを一つと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call ourselves one.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 美しんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! It's so beautiful.
許し合える刹那 夜はきらめく
In this forgiving moment, the night sparkles.
雨、晴れ、カレイド まばたかない空
Rain, shine, kaleidoscope, a blinking-free sky.
揺さぶる旅路は 今日は
Today, this shaking journey...
君と歩くことなんだ
is about walking with you.
「ただいま」を聞けば 「おかえり」って叫ぶよ
Hearing "I'm home", I'll shout "Welcome back".
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that obvious?
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! It shines bright.
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
What fills the darkness is you, is me.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! It shines bright.
悔しさも愛しさも連れて おいで
Bring along both frustration and affection.
風、夢、羽ばたけ 踏み立てるさ
Wind, dreams, spread your wings and step forward.
ささやかな祈りは 光
Our humble prayers become light.
終わりなき兆し 君と飛び込んでゆく
An endless sign, diving in with you.
素敵なスタートさ ここから これから
It's a wonderful start, from here, from now.
Our Bright Parade, Parade, Parade!
のじゃー！
Noja~!
なんか感動しちゃうのじゃ。
I'm getting kind of emotional.
わし画面の前にいたのにさ、
Even though I was right in front of the screen,
もしかしてこれから先3Dになったりしたら
what if, moving forward, I become 3D or something
この後ろの前でリアルのライブとかで歌えちゃったりするんじゃろうか。
and get to sing at a real live show right in front of this backdrop?
いつかわしがステージに立っての、ステージに立っての、それでなの、
If I ever stand on stage... stand on stage, and then...
それを見たわしのなかからかつてなわしみたいにこのライブに憧れる人が出ちゃったりするんじゃろうか。
I wonder if someone seeing that will yearn for this live show just like I once did.
まだまだめちゃくちゃほやほやの新参じゃけど、
I'm still a super fresh newcomer, but...
そういうね、わしに憧れる子がもし出てちゃうかも、出てきちゃうかもしれないのじゃ。
maybe, just maybe, someone who looks up to me might appear.
それってすごいことなのじゃ。
That would be amazing.
That's an amazing thing.
すごいことなのじゃ。
It's such a big deal.
まだわしデビューして1週間なのに。
Even though I only debuted a week ago.
すごいことなのじゃ。
It's amazing.
ねえ、不思議な話、運命みたいなのじゃなんかのじゃ。
Hey, it's such a mysterious story, almost like fate.
ねえ、わしが僕らになった。
Hey, "I" became "we".
すごいことなのじゃ。
That's incredible.
すごい嬉しいのじゃ。
I'm so happy.
今こうやって、ね、リアルタイムで、アーカイブでもきっと見てる人もたくさんいるじゃろし。
Right now, like this, in real-time, and I'm sure many are watching the archive too.
いっぱいの人が見てくれて、推しのこととか遊び回り隊のことね、応援してくれて、
So many people came to watch and supported me, my oshis, and Ashobimawaritai,
まだだってわしたち出会って1週間じゃよ。
We've only known each other for a week, you know.
まだ1週間なのにさ、まだ1週間なのにさ、
Even though it's only been a week...
わしたちのことをさ、応援してくれる人こんなにいっぱいる。すごい嬉しいのじゃ。
There are so many people supporting us. I'm so happy!
こんなにいっぱいの人がわしたちのことを応援してくれてるのじゃ。
So many people are supporting us like this.
すごいありがたいことなのじゃ。
It's such a wonderful thing.
ありがとうなのじゃ。
Thank you so much.
ねえ、こうい1週間じゃの。
Hey, what a week it's been.
でもこれからも好きもっともっとたくさんあるよ。
But there'll be so much more ahead.
もっともっと長い間お主らと一緒にいるよ。うん。
I'll be with you guys for a long time. Yeah.
うん、応援してくれて嬉しいのじゃ。うん。
Yeah, I'm so happy you're supporting me. Yeah.
これからも、これからもいっぱいいっぱい応援してほしいのじゃ。
From now on too, I want you to keep supporting us a lot.
わしたちのことこれからもいっぱいいっぱい応援してほしいのじゃ。
I want you to keep supporting us a lot.
よろしくお願いしますのじゃ。うん。無理だけはしないでね。
Please keep supporting us. Yeah, just don't push yourselves too hard.
うん、あのね、あの、無理しないように、あの、1週間に1回か2回、ちゃんとお休みも入れますのじゃ。
Um, you know, so you don't overdo it, I'll take breaks once or twice a week.
結構すでに心配してくれてる人がいる、わしのこと。
There are already quite a few people worrying about me.
うん、大丈夫かなって心配してくれてる人もいるし、
Yeah, some people worry if I'll be okay,
わしも慣れるまではね、ちゃんとお休みを取りつつも、長い間ね、うん。
and until I get used to it, while taking proper breaks, for a long time, yeah.
長い間お主らと一緒にいたいと思ってるから、
I want to be with you guys for a long time,
お休みをしつつ、配信をしつつ、うん、お主らとずっと一緒にいれたいいなって思いますのじゃ。
so I hope to keep taking breaks, streaming, and staying together with you guys.
うん、うん、ありがとなのじゃ。うん、頑張るのじゃ。うん。
Yeah, yeah, thank you. Yeah, I'll do my best. Yeah.
ありがとうなのじゃ。よいしょ。
Thank you so much. There we go.
じゃあ、おしらせ、おしらせ2度め、どーん！
Now, an announcement... Announcement the second, boom!
10月4日日曜日20時から歌枠をやるのじゃ。
On Sunday, October 4th at 8 PM, we'll be having a singing relay!
遊びまわり隊デビュー記念歌枠リレーを行いますのじゃ。
We're holding an Ashobimawaritai debut singing relay!
遊びまわり隊の4人で歌をね、なんか何分かずつ歌って、最後に4人で歌う歌枠リレーを
The four of us from Ashobimawaritai will each sing for a few minutes, and finally, do a singing relay together,
やりますのじゃ！10月4日のは20時から開けいといてほしいですのじゃ、お願いしますのじゃ！
we'll do it! Please keep October 4th open from 8 PM onwards, I'm begging you!
のじゃ。あとね、明日はね、8番出口で遊ぶのじゃ。
Noja. Also, tomorrow, I'll be playing 'The Exit 8'.
ホラゲ、ホラーゲームみたいな。やったことないから
Horage, a horror game. I've never played one before,
どういうゲームかかんないけれど、異変を見つけるゲームみたいなのじゃ。
so I don't know what kind of game it is, but it seems like a game where you find anomalies.
あ、一応言っとく。配信の最初にも言ったんだけれど、
Ah, just in case, I mentioned it at the start of the stream too,
あの歌枠はジョイサウンドさんのカラオケ音源を使わせていただいてるので、歌唱部分、お歌を歌ってる部分の切り抜きは、
the singing streams use JOYSOUND's karaoke audio sources, so clipping the singing parts—the parts where I'm singing—is
禁止なのじゃ。歌ってるところは動画で切り抜かないで、
forbidden. Please do not clip the parts where I'm singing in your videos.
もしなんか拡散したいなって思ったらURLをツイートするのじゃ！
If you want to spread the word, tweet the URL!
URLをツイートして、ここの何分何秒からのまるまるって曲めっちゃ良かったんだよねって、ツイートしてほしいのじゃ。
Tweet the URL saying, 'The song from such-and-such minute to such-and-such minute was amazing,' I'd love for you to tweet that.
で、無理ツイートしてる人を見かけたら、あのそっとしておいてほしいのじゃ。あの、そのへんのね、あのダメだよっていうのをやってる人へ注意するのはね、あのきっと会社のほうがね、
And if you see someone posting it illegally, please just leave them be. Warning people who are doing things they shouldn't is something the company,
うん、やってくださるので、あのそういう人を見つけても何も言わずにスルーするのがインターネットリテラシーの高き者、
yeah, will take care of, so even if you find such people, ignoring them without saying anything is the mark of someone with high internet literacy,
うん、インテリリテラシーの高いサラマンダーの、お主らメラ組のお主らはそういう人を見ても、しー、なのだじゃ。うん。
yeah, salamanders with high internet literacy, you guys in Mela-gumi, even if you see such people, just 'shh,' okay? Yeah.
そして、お願いしますのじゃ。
And please, I'm asking you.
ほらね、苦手。どれぐらい苦手かというとね、
See, I'm bad at it. How bad am I?
あのトースターが怖いぐらい苦手。うん。トースターが怖いぐらい苦手。
I'm so bad at it that even toasters scare me. Yeah. Toasters scare me that much.
トースターでビビっちゃうぐらいびっくり系のホラーが苦手だから、ちょっとどうなるかわかんないけれど、
I'm so bad at jump scares that even a toaster would startle me, so I don't know how it's gonna go,
どうなるかなあって思ってるけれど、うん。うん。まあ、
I'm wondering how it'll turn out, yeah. Yeah. Well,
まあ、楽しみにしていてほしいのじゃ。
I hope you're looking forward to it.
頑張りますのじゃ。
I'll do my best.
今日の配信はこのへんでおしまいにしようかな。おしまいにするのじゃ。
I think I'll wrap up today's stream around here. I'll call it a day.
また明日、また明日会いたいのだじゃ。また明日会いたいのだじゃ。
Tomorrow, I want to see you again tomorrow. I want to see you tomorrow.
そして見てくれた人いっぱい。コメント、あのね、あの、アーカイブとか歌枠だからアーカイブとか聴いて、あっこの曲のこここ部分の
And everyone who watched, so many comments, um, you know, archives or singing streams, listening to the archives and saying 'this part of this song...'
みらちゃん好きだなみたいなあったら
If there's something like "I love Mela-chan,"
あのコメント欄の感想ね、わし見てるからね。
I always check the comments and feedback, you know.
あのここが好きなのじゃあみたいな感じでね、
Like, "This is what I love about you,"
あのコメントで教えてくれると嬉しいのじゃ。
I'd be so happy if you could let me know in the comments.
お願いしますなのじゃ！
Please do!
たくさん聞いてほしいのじゃ。のじゃ。
I hope you'll listen to it a lot. Noja.
じゃあ最後の挨拶、さらばじゃでおしまいにしますのじゃ！
Well then, for our final greeting, let's wrap it up with a farewell!
お主ら行くぞ！行くぞ！行くぞー！
You guys, here we go! Here we go! Here we go!
今日も配信見てくれてありがとうございましたなのじゃ。
Thank you so much for watching today's stream too, noja.
それでは…さらばじゃあ！
And with that... Farewell!